Choose, Akira. Either live with me,
or die with her.
（飛鳥(あすか) 了(りょう)）選べ 明(あきら)！
この俺と生きるか
その女と死ぬかを！
（明と了のうなり声）
（携帯電話の着メロ）
（不動(ふどう) 明）ん？
お前の携帯だ 母親の着メロ
（明）うう…
It's your phone.
It's your mother's ringtone.
I set it as that.
（了）俺が設定した
（明のうなり声）
（電話の呼び出し音）
（不動香織(かおり)）あっ 明？
Oh, Akira?
（留守電）ただいま
電話に出ることができません
The person you have called is unavailable.
ピーという発信音のあとに
お名前と ご用件をお話しください
Please, leave your name,
and message after the tone.
（発信音）
（香織）明？ 母さんよ
お父さんから 連絡はないよね？
Akira, it's your mother.
Have you heard from your father?
（英語：客室乗務員）
お客様 電話をお切りください
（英語：香織）
ごめんなさい すぐに
（香織）東京 27日 14時に
成田(なりた)に着くから 詳しくは そこで
I arrive in Tokyo at 2:00 p.m.
on the 27th. I'll tell you more then.
（通話が切れる音）
Dad?
（明）父さん？
You should worry about your mother.
（了）
案じるべきは 母親のほうだ
（明）ん？
（了）今や 誰でも
悪魔になる可能性がある
Anyone could turn into a demon now.
人間を信じるな
親も その女もだ
Don't trust humans.
Or your parents or that girl.
（明）んん…
The only one you should trust is me.
お前が信じていいのは
俺だけだ！
Come, Akira
（牧村(まきむら)太郎(たろう)）明兄ちゃん
何で おかか動いてんの？
Akira,
why do dried bonito flakes move?
まだ生きてんだよ
Because they're alive.
They're writhing in agony
from being shaved so thin.
こんなに薄く削られても
苦しみ もだえているんだ！
（太郎）え～！！
ホント～ ウソでしょ？
Really?
You're lying.
（明）ウソでしょ？
（不動礼次郎(れいじろう)）ホントだぞ～
じゃあ どうして動いてんだ？
It's true.
Why do you think they're moving?
（牧村美樹(みき)）本当だよ
It's the truth.
撮影スタジオ行って
お風呂で溺れそうになって…
I went to the studio
and almost drowned in the bathtub.
（牧村ノエル）美樹 父さんは
美樹を信じてるが―
Miki, I believe you,
but you haven't taken
any weird drugs, right?
変なクスリとか やってないよな？
（美樹）絶対やらないよ！
I'd never do that.
（牧村亜樹子(あきこ)）ＧＰＳでは
うちから出てないみたいだけど
According to your GPS,
you never left the house.
携帯 忘れたのかも
Maybe I forgot my phone.
でも どうしても
そのあとが思い出せないんだ
I can't remember
what happened after that.
でも 私 行ったのよ
But I did go there.
酔っぱらうと
忘れちゃうんだって
People forget when they get drunk.
んっ 太郎！
Taro!
（亜樹子）明くん
今日 何時に出るの？
What time are you leaving today, Akira?
９時に 了が迎えに来ます
Ryo's picking me up at 9:00.
香織に言っておいて
Tell Kaori that she's being awful.
ちょっと
ひどすぎるんじゃないのって
日本にいる間―
And to come see her best friend
一度くらい 大親友の私に
顔を見せてって
at least once while she's in Japan.
Akira, you have a mother?
明兄ちゃん お母さんいるの？
（ノエル）明くんの
お父さんと お母さんは―
Akira's parents are brilliant doctors.
立派な お医者さんなんだよ
世界中で 困っている人を
助けてあげてるから―
They help people in need
all over the world,
めったに日本に
帰ってこられないんだ
so they can rarely come back to Japan.
The people who always send shoes
for Akira, right?
いつも 明兄ちゃんに
靴送ってくる人？
医者って もうかるんでしょ？
ドラッグ 横流ししたりしてさ
Doctors make tons of money
selling illegal drugs and stuff, right?
太郎！ 意味分かって
言ってんの！？
Do you even know what you're saying?!
ドラッグで
パワーアップできるんだよね！
You can get stronger with drugs, right?
（明たち）ああ…
パワーアップだ！
-Power up!
-That's enough weird news for today.
変なニュース 聞きかじんな
でっ ＤＶだよ 兄ちゃん
That's domestic violence!
Want me to use demon power
to turn you into dried bonito flakes?
本当のデビール力(りょく)で
おかかにしてやろうか？
（太郎）
いえ 間に合ってます！
No, I have enough!
（明と亜樹子の笑い声）
（ノエル･亜樹子･太郎の笑い声）
（ドアが開く音）
（美樹）明くん
Akira.
About the thing from before...
さっきのことなんだけど…
You were there at that studio,
too, weren't you?
明くんもいなかった？
そのスタジオに
私 明くんに
助けられたような気がしてて…
I have a feeling you saved me.
うわっ！
そうだ 俺が助けた
Yeah. I saved you.
（美樹）うう…
（明）ううう
（美樹）んっ もう！
Jeez.
（明）
夢だよ 夢 どうかしてるぜ
It was just a dream.
You're crazy.
（美樹）ふっ
ふう…
（明）美樹は 大丈夫だ
昨日のことは 夢だと思ってる
Miki's fine.
She thinks yesterday was a dream.
お前が ＧＰＳも操作してくれて
アリバイも完璧だ
Thanks to you manipulating the GPS,
we have a perfect alibi.
あいつは 悪魔を見たのか？
Did she see the demon?
（明）
見てねえよ 何の記憶もねえ
No, she didn't.
She doesn't remember anything.
（美樹）私 明くんに
助けられたような気がしてて…
I have a feeling you saved me.
What?
なっ！ あ…
I'll let it slide this time.
（了）今日は 見のがしてやる
ああ～…
（香織）こうやって結ぶと
ほどけにくいのよ
Tie it like this and it won't come undone.
（明）はあ…
Akira, come and join us
when you grow up.
（礼次郎）明も大きくなって
父さんたちを追いかけてこい
待ってるぞ
We'll be waiting.
はっ
（荒い息）
（香織）早く 早く
Hurry, hurry.
（香織）しっかり結んで
ほどけないように
Tie it tight so it doesn't come undone.
（明）大きくなる
I'll grow up.
速くなって お父さんと
お母さんに追いつくよ
I'll grow up fast and catch up with you,
Mom and Dad.
（無線の声）
（カイム）
先を越されてしまったな
We were beaten to the punch.
It might be quicker
to find the man who was in that footage.
あのビデオに映っていた男を
見つけたほうが早そうだ
（ミーコの荒い息）
（車が走り去る音）
（ククン）
これ 君が植えたんだよね
You planted these, right?
何？
What?
俺 向かいの棟なんだよ
I'm in the tower over there.
こっちの棟も古いのに
つっかえ棒で モダンに見えるな
This tower is old, too,
but it looks modern
with these supporting rods.
変な動物
飼ってるヤツいるだろ？
Is there a guy with a weird pet?
おかしな鳴き声が聞こえる
（ミーコ）はっ！
I hear weird whimpering sometimes.
だから何？ 向こう行ってよ！
What is it that you want? Go away.
（ククン）あ…
ごめんね突然
いつも見てんだ
I'm sorry
It was out of the blue
I've always been watching
The snapdragons here are vibrant
As if it's an incident
ここの金魚草 鮮やか
まるで事件さ
全部一人で毎日
The way you water all of them
水をあげ続ける
君の姿が素敵で
All on your own every day is enchanting
I want to say that
それが言いたいから
気持ちが沈むね
My heart sinks
俺もここの住人だけど
I live here, too, and whenever
I see these flowers, I get encouraged
この花見るたび
もらえてんだ勇気
いつも遠慮がちで
I'm always reserved and hide behind people
人の後ろ影にばっか隠れて
思い通りうまく話したりは
できないけど
I can't talk the way I want to
But I still wanna say
それでも言いたいんだ
したくない後悔
Don't wanna regret
これまで何べんも
イモ引いてばっかの状態
I kept on getting intimidated
Over and over again until now
本当は俺だって
もっとやってやれるって
Even I can actually do better
他のチームのメンバーにも
I'm not outdone by the other guys
In the team in any way
決して負けてたりしないって
いっつも叫んでんだ
心の内側
Always screaming inside my heart
But it won't get heard
だけどそれじゃ届かない
マジ言わなきゃこの口から
Seriously, I have to say it with my mouth
I hate myself
俺は俺が嫌いさ
いつもしてるウジウジ
I always mope around
わかってる変わりたい
これでもやってんだ一途に
I know I want to change
Still, I'm trying with all my heart
俺の名前はマユタ
My name is Mayuta
Mayuta, Mayuta, Mayuta
マユタ マユタ マユタ
いつの間にかククン
Before I knew it, I'm Kukun
Treated as if I'm everyone's hanger-on
扱い まるで皆の金魚の糞(ふん)
なじんじまった名前
The name I got used to
気づきゃ こんな街の中で
誰も俺のやることなんて
I've noticed
There's no one looking at what I do
見ちゃいないし
気にもとめてねー
They don't even take notice
Notice me more
もっと俺を見てよ
誰か俺のことを見ててよ
Someone, please, notice me
不安なんだ常にどこでも
I'm always anxious wherever I am
何をしててもいつも
あと一歩のとこで
No matter what I do, I can't take that
Step forward when it's just one more push
なかなか踏み出せない
本当は俺も夢見てんだ
光り輝いた未来
Truthfully, I have a dream, too
A bright shining future
今は未だ繭(まゆ)に包まれてる
そんなガラクタ
Still wrapped in a cocoon
Even if I'm junk like that
でも いつか目指す
I'll aim to become a butterfly
Just like it says on my fingers
この指の文字の通り
バタフライ
ワムもガビもバボもヒエも
きっとさせる仰天
I'll amaze Wamu, Gabi, Babo, and Hie
Draw a vision in a dream
I'll do it
夢に描くビジョン
俺はすんだ 俺にだけの挑戦
A challenge just for me
You get it, right?
わかるだろ なぁ
君はこれが聞こえてるだろ
You hear this, right?
今歌う俺のことが
ちゃんと見えてるんだろ？
You can see me as I sing this, right?
誰かこんな俺のことも
ちゃんと好きになって
Someone, please, like me as I am
And let me like myself more
俺に俺自身のことを
もっと好きにならせてくれよ
（ミーコの泣き声）
えっ 何？ ごめん 俺のせい？
What? Sorry. Is it my fault?
（客室乗務員）皆様 本日は
当エアラインをご利用いただき―
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you very much
for flying with our airline today.
誠に ありがとうございました
皆様に またお会いできる日を―
Our entire crew look forward
客室乗務員一同
心より お待ち申し上げております
to seeing you onboard again
in the near future.
（英語のアナウンス）
（空港作業員）はっ！
おい 大丈夫か？
Hey, are you all right?
ふわあっ！
明
Akira.
（乗客１）ああ！
（乗客２）何？
What?
（英語：乗客３）押すなよ
（乗客１）きゃー！！
What's going on?
（乗客４）何やってんだ
（英語：乗客３）
あいつ おかしいぞ
か… おり…
Kaori...
あなた！？
Darling?
（乗客３）あう！
（乗客たちの悲鳴）
Crap!
（乗客４）やばい！
（乗客５）何だよ！
What is this?!
（乗客たちの悲鳴）
Darling!
（香織）あなた！
あなた やめて！
Darling, stop!
Please, Reijiro! Stop!
お願い 礼次郎 やめて！
（礼次郎の足音）
（香織）あ… あああ… あ…
やめて！ 礼次郎！
Please, don't, Reijiro!
（礼次郎）
はあああ… へへへ…
（香織）あああ！ ああ…
（香織のうめき声）
（運転手の悲鳴）
I WANT TO ASK YOU SOMETHING.
CALL ME WHEN YOU READ THIS.
（ノックする音）
美樹ちゃん いい？
Miki, can I come in?
うん いいよ
Yup.
Come in.
いただいたリンゴ むくけど
-I'm going to peel the apples we received.
-I don't need any.
私 いいや
（亜樹子）ん…
撮影スタジオって―
Did you go to the photo studio
with that cameraman from before?
この間のカメラマンさんと
一緒に行ったの？
（美樹）あ…
思い出せたら
聞かせてくれる？
Can you tell me about if you remember?
うん ありがと 母さん
Yup.
Thanks, Mom.
（ククン）父さんが
働けなくなっちゃって―
My dad can no longer work.
山手(やまのて)だと ラベルもキャップも
はずしてあって きれいだからさ
They remove the labels and caps
in Yamanote to get them clean.
That was a good song.
さっきの いい歌だった
Really?
ホント！？
私の歌だった
It was about me.
（ククン）そうだよ
That's right.
（ミーコ）ん…
私のことも歌ってくれたけど
全部 私のことだった
You sang about me, too,
but everything was about me.
（ククン）ん…
私も黒田(くろだ)ミキっていうの
My name is also Miki Kuroda.
あ…
（ミーコの祖母）ミキー！
Miki!
牧村美樹は
ホント すごいけど―
Miki Makimura really is amazing,
何か１つだけは…
陸上くらいは 私も勝ちたい
but I want to win
at least one track event.
そうじゃないと
私 ミキになれない…
Otherwise I can't be Miki.
I'll be Miko for the rest of my life.
一生 ミーコのまんま
そんなことない
That's not true.
（鼻をすする音）
君 めちゃめちゃ かわいいし
すごく努力家のミキだよ！
You're a really cute, hardworking Miki.
（ミーコ）は… は…
（明）寂しかったけれど―
I was lonely...
...but I was proud to think
my mom had a job helping everyone.
俺の母さんは みんなの役に立つ
仕事をしてるんだっていう―
誇らしい気持ちがあった
It's rare for her to call.
電話は 珍しいんだ
中学ん時 母さんの声聞いたのは
２回だけだったからな
I only heard my mom's voice twice
when I was in junior high.
それは少ないのか？
（明）えっ？
That's not a lot?
俺は 親ってものを
知らないからな
I don't know anything about parents.
（明）あ… 悪い
Sorry.
ただの事実だ
It's just a fact.
（旅行客１）遅いぞ！
-Why is it so late?
-It's already been so long.
（旅行客２）もう ずいぶん
たってるみたいなんだけど
We're confirming things now.
Please, wait a little longer.
（空港職員）
ただいま確認しております
もう少々 お待ちください
おかしいな
That's odd.
（携帯電話の着メロ）
母さん？ 今どこ？
Mom?
Where are you?
明 整備工場だ
It's at the maintenance shop.
（了）気をつけろ
Be careful.
（明）分かってる
I know.
来ないで 明
Don't come, Akira.
Mom.
母さん！
私は 死んだの！
I'm already dead.
（明）
うっ… どういうことだ 母さん
What do you mean, Mom?
ごめんなさい 明
ずっと ほったらかしで
I'm sorry, Akira.
For neglecting you all this time.
あなたを抱いてあげたかった
涙を拭いてあげたかった
I wanted to hug you.
To wipe away your tears.
でも 私は 死んでしまったの
But... I'm dead now.
-Mom!
-Akira!
母さん！
（了）明！
来ないで！ 明
Don't come, Akira!
うっ…
（女）あああ…
（少年）うううう
（英語：少女）怖いよ 怖いよ
Help us.
（男）助けてくれ
（英語：少女）
お母さん お父さん
I'm cold. It's cold here.
（少年）寒いよ ここは寒いよ
（女）どうして
死ななきゃならないの？
Why do I have to die?
（男）帰してくれ！
まだ仕事が終わってないんだ
Let me go. I still have work to do.
あっ！！
（礼次郎）あ… きら…
Akira...
父さん！？ 父さん！
Dad?
Dad!
（礼次郎）私は ヒトじゃない…
I'm not a human.
あなた…
Darling.
デーモン！？
A demon?
（礼次郎）うへへへ
母さんが 母さんが
食いたかったんだ
I wanted to...
I wanted to eat your mother.
はあ… はあ… はあ…
父さん… はあ…
Dad.
父さん
よくも俺の… 俺の！！
How dare you?
How dare you?!
ううう…
（デビルマンの荒い息）
明！ あなたまで！
Akira... You, too?
No. I'm not a demon. I'm Devilman.
違う 俺は悪魔じゃない
デビルマンだ！
はっ！
デビル！？
Devil?
My heart is still human.
（デビルマン）
俺の心は 人間のままだ
俺は 悪魔に勝ったんだ
I won against the demon.
だから父さんも！
父さんも勝ってくれ！ 悪魔に！
So you can, too, Dad. Win!
Beat the demon!
あ… あ… あ… あああ…
（礼次郎の絶叫）
あなた！
Darling!
で… 出てけ 出てけー！
Get out! Get out!
やめろ！
（英語：少女）怖いよう
Stop!
I'm scared!
It's agonizing!
苦しい
あきらめよう
Let's give up.
負けるな 父さん！
悪魔なんかに！
Don't lose, Dad.
Don't lose to the demon that killed Mom!
母さんを殺したヤツなんかに！
（礼次郎のもだえる声）
Reijiro!
礼次郎！
Dad!
父さん！
悪魔めえええ！！
Damn demon!
礼次郎！
Reijiro!
（デビルマン）うっ ああ…
来るぞ 明！
It's coming!
あっ！
Ryo!
了！
（ジンメン）
人間が悪魔に勝つだと？
A human winning against a demon?
あるわけねーだろ
そんなこと！
There's no way that could happen.
弱い人間の心で 俺を殺せるか？
I cannot be killed by a weak human heart.
Cry.
泣け！ おら おら おら！
（少年と少女の悲鳴）
There! There!
Akira! We're already dead!
明 私たちは もう死んでるの！
（ジンメン）おら おら！
（デビルマン）くっ
（英語）お願い
ママに会うまでは殺さないで
あ…
了？
Ryo.
What a horrible human.
How dare he shoot a child's face?
（ジンメン）ひどい人間だ
子供の顔を撃ち抜くなんて
明！ あれは人間じゃない！
ただのデスマスクだ！
Akira, those aren't humans.
They're just death masks.
（デビルマン）ぬう…
やれ 明
もう お前の母親ではないんだ！
Do it, Akira.
She's not your mother anymore.
（デビルマン）ああ…
お前がやらなければ 俺がやるぞ
いいのか！？
I'll do it if you won't.
Do you hear me?
母さんを…
Mom.
Akira. Run to me.
明 走ってきて
（香織）ぎゅっと結んで
Tie it tightly.
私は もう死んでるの
ここへ来て 救って！
I'm already dead.
Come save me.
母さん！
Mom!
（ジンメン）黙れ 人間
Shut up, human.
（香織）ん… 明 来て
Akira.
Come.
It's something a crybaby like you
could never do.
（ジンメン）お前みたいな
泣き虫には できない相談だ
明 おいで
Akira, come.
母さんを助けて
Save me.
（デビルマン）
はあ… うわああああ！
（香織）生きて 明 愛してる！
Live, Akira.
I love you.
（明の泣き声）
（デビルマン）ぬうああああ！
父さん！ 母さーん！
Dad! Mom!
うわああああ！
（ジンメン）ああ… あああ…
俺は デビルマン！
I'm Devilman.
人の命を奪う者を許しはしない！
I won't tolerate those
who take people's lives.
（ジンメン）ぐっ
ごめん ごめんよ…
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
（クラブの音楽）
（人々の騒ぎ声）
連れてきてくれて ありがとう！
（ククン）あ… ふん…
Thanks for bringing me here.
これで記録が
伸びた人がいるって聞いて―
I heard someone
got faster after coming here,
来てみたかったんだ
so I wanted to try it, too.
喜んでくれて よかった
I'm glad you're happy.
えっ？ 何？ 聞こえない！
What? I can't hear you.
踊ろう！
Let's dance.
ふふ いいよ！
（ククン）あっ
Sure.
ふふ
意外とダンスも得意なんだ
I'm a pretty good dancer.
（ミーコ）ふっ ふふふふ
（耳のデーモン）うううう…
（耳のデーモンの叫び声）
はっ！
&lrm;
&lrm;日本語字幕　後藤 太郎
Subtitles by
Kristine Kenmochi